Listen, it sounded like the brown-
breasted bottle-beaked hooting owl.
Sherman, did you really bring me all
the way out here just to look at birds?
I thought you liked birds.
Yes, but sometimes there are
other things I'd like to see.
- Like what?
- Like a movie.
Shh. Hear that? The owl is near.
- Sherman.
- Yes?
Does it have unusually large eyes?
Oh, yes. I'd say so.
It's a nocturnal predator.
And a giant pointy beak...
and fur?
You know, Treena,
I'd be up for a movie.
He did it. Scooby-Doo
captured the monster.
Scooby-Dooby-Doo.
It's not a real monster.
It's actually Miss Thelmer,
the company accountant.
My plan was perfect.
How did you ever...?
Hi, Mom. Can't talk, exposition time.
What? Hang on.
Will you take the wrap-up,
Freddie? I'm back.
Miss Thelmer is actually
a corporate spy.
She pretended to be the so-called
Chemical Creep to scare people away...
while she stole the
company's secret formulas.
From now on, the only books you'll be
keeping will be from the prison library.
Well, another successful
case is closed.
All right, dude, I say we celebrate
with a party at the Burger Binge.
Yeah.
Burger Binge, Burger Binge.
I've got a better idea.
Shaggy, you remember
my little sister Madelyn?
Little doe-eyes Dinkley?
Like, how could I forget?
That's not nice.
She really liked you.
I'm sorry, Vel. Mads is a sweet kid.
We'll have to look her up sometime.
That time is now. My mom
wants us to check up on her.
- Is something wrong?
- You might say that.
Madelyn's going to a special
school for stage magicians.
And, well, according to my mom...
the school's being
threatened by a griffin.
Zoinks. Not a griffin.
I mean, anything but a griffin.
Like, what's a griffin?
A creature that's
half eagle, half lion.
Couldn't it make up its mind?
It's a legend, Shaggy.
Mostly from medieval times.
It doesn't really exist.
I've heard that rap before.
Come on, we can't say
no to Velma's mom.
But can't we say yes
to a burger party first?
Burger Binge, Burger Binge,
Burger Binge.
All right, Scooby-Doo, go fish.
I can't, Shaggy.
- Why not?
- I don't have a fishing pole.
Your next turn is 5 miles ahead.
Watch out for the dips in the road...
not including the ones in the
back seat. Ha, ha. That's a joke.
Pothole.
Watch out. Will you please
keep your eyes on the road?
I'm not sure about the Mystery
Machine's new GPS, Fred.
Where did you get your
license, from a hobo?
I know, isn't it awesome?
This is the magician school?
It looks like a castle.
It is a castle.
O'Flannery Manor
originated in Ireland...
where it was known for
its mystical happenings.
Back in the 19th century,
its owner, Lord Seamus O'Flannery...
had it transported to
America brick by brick.
It says here that Seamus
O'Flannery practiced dark magic.
Pretty creepy, eh, Scoob?
Yeah, creepy.
It gets creepier.
When he passed on...
Seamus had himself entombed in
an island crypt on the nearby lake.
Man, am I happy we
forgot our swimsuits.
The castle was auctioned recently and cost
the magician a pretty penny to buy it.
Turn left at the next pine tree.
Left. Wake up, people.
Are you sure about this?
Relax, scarf boy,
we're taking the scenic route.
Everybody calls it
a scarf. It's an ascot.
Hang a right at the weeping willow.
Right.
Veer left at the rhododendron.
Make a U-turn at the skunk.
- Ha, ha, ha.
- Fred, this can't be right.
I better check the
warranty on this thing.
Hey, look, it's the
road to the school.
There it is.
- Jinkies.
- Velma.
Madelyn.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
You look so adorable.
Oh, my gosh. I can't believe it.
You're really here. My big sister.
- Hi, Madelyn.
- Hi, Daphne.
Hi, Freddie.
Hi, Scooby.
Uh... Ha...
Hi, Shaggy.
Hi, Madelyn.
Welcome, everyone.
I'm Whirlen Merlin,
maestro of the magical academy.
Alakazam.
And this lovely lady is my
former stage assistant, Crystal.
Hm. I guess this school doesn't
have much of a dress code.
Yeah.
Greetings. I teach
prestidigitary assistantship.
I'm also in charge of caring
for our magical co-stars.
This is Vernon, our star performer.
But don't worry,
he's a real pussycat.
Nice to meet you.
Yipe.
1, 2, 3...
4. Phew.
We better hurry. It's almost dark.
Don't wanna be around when
you-know-what drops by.
All right, Marlon.
Marlon here is our
resident stagehand.
He runs things behind the scenes.
We wouldn't have a show without him.
Marlon, please see to
our guests' luggage.
Already finished, boss.
See you inside.
Yeah, Scoob, like,
maybe we better go in.
Repeat after me.
Open, sesame.
Open, sesame
I hope you find your time at
O'Flannery Castle exciting.
It's the grandest magic
academy in existence.
Gee, I wonder where
all the students are.
I don't know.
In their rooms, where it's safe.
This is Miss Alma Rumblebuns.
She was custodian of the
castle before I bought it.
And now she's a housekeeper
to the students.
This facility allows
performing animals only.
Oh, that's okay. Scooby's
been through training school.
Yeah. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Whoa. Whoa!
Oh, like, he was dropped on
his head when he was a puppy.
Oh, very well. I will
show you your rooms.
Cone Castle commercial, take one.
We're Cone Castle cones
And we're healthy for you
Run to your grocer and pick up a few
Mixing grown-up flavors
Into kids' ice cream
- Liver.
- Onion.
- Broccoli.
- We're a gourmet lover's dream.
Hold it, hold it.
Pardon me for halting
the festivities...
but I distinctly remember paying
for a buttered Brussels sprout.
Ooh, um, sorry, I'm here.
Oopsie daisy.
Oh, for heaven's sakes.
Can someone please manage this mess?
And you there, your cone is crumpled.
Yes?
Mr. Curdles, it's me, Amos.
Remember when you told me to
call if any more students arrived?
- I saw 4 kids and a dog.
- 4 kids and a dog, eh? Heh, heh.
Whirlen must be awfully desperate
if he's enrolling animals.
Perhaps they'll get another
visit from the you-know-what.
He's showing up almost nightly these
days and getting bolder each time.
I'd hate to think what
could happen tonight.
I'm sure you'll let me know.
Will no one dab up this dairy?
They say Lord O'Flannery
practiced real magic.
And that he had many secrets
built into the castle walls.
Legend has it that he even conjured
up a griffin to protect it...
and housed the monster in that old
tower... called the Griffin's Roost.
Why doesn't Whirlen Merlin knock it down
and put up a student union or something?
He's hoping to restore it someday.
But until then, it's off-limits.
His career goes all the way
back to when he was a kid.
He started with
neighborhood puppet shows.
Oh, and over here is his trophy case.
This is Whirlen Merlin
when he was onstage.
Isn't he awesome?
I had no idea you were
so into magic, Madelyn.
At least you've finally
settled on something.
Where were you last
semester, clown college?
Heh, heh. Yeah, so I've
done some soul searching.
Not everyone is born with a
mystery book in her hand, Velma.
Well, I think magic is really cool.
I've always been fascinated
by how it's done.
Just as Velma loves
to solve mysteries...
I love to uncover the secrets of magic,
and this is the perfect school for that.
What about that griffin? Mom said...
Mom's just dramatic.
It's a silly old myth.
That's our dinner bell.
Alakazam.
And because you're our
special guests of honor...
I've asked the chef...
That's me.
To prepare a royal feast.
A feast.
Like, I think he said the magic word.
The guests of honor almost
outnumber the students.
And where are the teachers?
A lot of them left thanks
to that scary old griffin...
which no one has
ever seen, of course.
Before we start,
a little dinner lighting.
Alakazam.
Far out. Dinner by candlelight.
How romantic.
Let's eat.
Gee, Scoob, I think it's
a little undercooked.
Do not worry, never fear.
Your favorite dish will now appear.
Pinch me, Scooby-Doo,
extra cheesy cheese pizza
with a side of pickles.
Scooby Snacks in cherry
sauce and whipped cream.
Ho, ho, ho.
Wow. Whirlen is amazing.
- Aw.
- I cooked it.
What's that?
It's a devil of a night out there.
The kind of night that invites ghosts
and goblins and other visitors.
Uh, Miss Rumblebuns,
is it okay if some of us
go back to our rooms?
I suppose so.
Psst. Shaggy, come on.
While everyone else is eating,
I wanna show you something special.
- Like, now?
- Yes, while the moon is still out.
I promise you're going to
find it very, very exciting.
You know, Madelyn, I find this
pizza very, very, very exciting.
Come on.
Are you sure you wanna go out
in the dark? It's kind of spooky.
Amos the groundskeeper
is always out after dark.
Yeah, well, that dude's
totally spooky too.
What I wanna show is something that
was brought here with the castle...
over 2 centuries ago.
Hurry, guys, it's right
around the bend.
Here we are.
I found a picture of this sundial
on one of the castle walls.
When the moon is full and
you twist it like so...
That's Seamus O'Flannery, the man who
brought the castle over here from Ireland.
Wow. Like, dig that crazy toothpick.
Shaggy, that's the magic staff used
to summon and control the griffin.
What? I thought you said
the griffin was a myth.
I didn't want the others
to be frightened.
I'm telling you because you're brave.
Brave? Shaggy? Brave?
Sorry.
Like, what's all this
gruesome graffiti?
It says, "Winged protector,
arise and guard this castle."
Don't look now.
But I think it's arisen.
Through here.
Down.
Good thinking, Shaggy.
Like, who's thinking?
Did you see how Whirlen Merlin made
that dessert appear out of nowhere?
Not really. I was watching Crystal.
All she did was point.
It's the way she did
it so effortlessly.
I can point too.
Usually when you do you
knock my glasses off.
Easy, Velma. She hasn't done
that in at least an hour.
Ha, ha. Very funny, scarf boy.
Griffin!
It's the griffin!
Oh, my gosh, there it is.
That's right, Daddy.
I told you it was real.
Holy Houdini.
Open sesame, open sesame.
Open sesame now.
This way, guys.
When I enrolled Maxwell in your school
I didn't expect dodging monsters...
to be a part of the curriculum.
Good day, sir.
But we didn't know
the griffin was real.
Poor Whirlen. There go
the rest of his students.
Where are you going?
Aren't we taking Madelyn
home because of the griffin?
No, Shaggy.
The griffin has us curious.
Oh, looks like school's out.
- Who's he?
- Calvin Curdles, the cone king.
He's been trying to buy O'Flannery Castle
since Whirlen beat him in the auction.
Alma, you look lovely as always.
Oh, here, have a
sardine in castor oil.
It will enhance your
lovely complexion.
Don't try to con me
with your cones, Calvin.
Thought I'd bring something
for the kiddies.
Oh. But I see there
aren't any kiddies left.
I told you, Curdles,
I'm not ready to sell.
Really?
Not even after your little
pest-control problem?
The magic academy has
been my dream for years.
And we're not about to give it up
for one little scare. Are we, gang?
- No way.
- Well... Uh...
Why do you want the
castle, Mr. Curdles?
Well, my inquisitive little miss...
my dream is to retool it
into my flagship restaurant.
Then I'll open more restaurants.
Soon I'll have kids
all over the world...
eating my vegetable and variety
meat-flavored ice-cream cones.
But won't the griffin scare
away all your customers?
Yes. Well, uh...
I really don't believe in
things I don't believe in.
Neither do we, Mr. Curdles.
Which is why we
intend to investigate.
Griffin or no griffin, my offer
won't be around forever, Whirlen.
I suggest you reconsider.
Soon.
Hmph.
Call me if you hear anything.
He's right. I don't know what to do.
We've got a school
and no one to teach.
You still have me.
I wouldn't mind taking
one of your classes.
- That might not be a bad idea.
- What?
We should take some classes
to learn more about magic.
It could help us with
our investigation.
We would be delighted to teach you.
The full faculty of the Whirlen Merlin
Academy of Magic is at your command.
Hm.
What in the world?
Whoa.
Daphne?
Hey, Vel.
What's going on?
I'm tired of being klutzy old Daphne.
From now on I'm dazzling Daphne.
Centered, controlled, graceful.
Does this have anything to do with
Fred going gaga over Crystal?
No.
Maybe.
Why are you snooping at this hour?
I thought you'd be doing the
sisterly slumber party with Madelyn.
It's great to see Mads again but we
don't seem to have that much in common.
Just between you and me,
she's kind of a nerd.
No kidding.
Once she gloms onto something,
there's no stopping her.
She's always over-analyzing every
little thing that attracts her attention.
Hmm. There's some gritty residue
on the floor. Could be a clue.
- It's rosin. Dancers put it on their shoes.
- I knew that.
Yeah, you and your sister
are like night and day.
It must be stuck.
- A little help?
- Sure.
Thanks. Nothing like a workout
to control the klutziness.
That wasn't klutziness.
That happened on its own.
Come on.
This stuff must have been shipped over
from Ireland along with the castle.
Some of this is more recent.
This photo album can't be more
than 20 years old. Jinkies.
Isn't that Miss Rumblebuns?
It's hard to tell. She's smiling.
Madelyn says Alma's
worked here all her life.
Even before Whirlen
won it in an auction.
This castle's like her home.
Oh, my gosh.
That's Mr. Curdles.
They must have been boyfriend
and girlfriend. It takes all kinds.
I guess.
- Ooh.
- Ew.
We have to build up our energy in
case we see that creepy griffin again.
Like, who can run away
on an empty stomach?
Not me.
I think we hit that kitchen
in the nick of time, Scoob.
Like, your tummy is growling.
Not my tummy.
Well, if it's not your tummy,
and it's not my tummy...
like, it's his tummy.
Scoob.
Zoinks. A dead end. Nowhere to hide.
Look.
Phew.
Hello.
Like, come on, Scoob,
make friends with the nice kitty cat.
Yikes!
On second thought,
let's let him eat in peace.
Hey, look.
Puppets.
Like, this must be where they
store their Halloween decorations.
Hey, Scoob, how many times
have we run into goons like this?
"And I would've got away with it too
if it weren't for you meddling kids."
"And your dog too."
What are you doing in here?
Like, uh, we were just...
No one is allowed in this room.
Not students, not visitors,
and especially not fleabags.
- Huh?
Like, dude, how do
you get out of here?
Scooby? Scooby-Doo, where are you?
Hey, who killed the light show?
Just me.
That was scary.
- Shaggy.
- Oh, dear.
What is this place?
It's my private workroom.
This is where I create props
and illusions for the students.
I heard noises and found
these 2 snooping around.
No harm done, Miss Alma. I'm happy
to give them a demonstration.
That's amazing.
Thank you. It's a 3-dimensional
volumetric display.
Think of it as an upgrade on,
you know, your traditional hologram.
Yes, my big brother's
quite the showman.
Alakazam.
That was a little illusion he
whipped up for my farewell tour.
- Wait, you two are brothers?
- Funny, isn't it?
I get stuck with the looks,
while lucky Marlon here, the brains.
Yeah, lucky me.
I'm in the early stages. Right now
I can only create small things.
But someday...
Hey, I just had a thought. Maybe the
griffin is just like a humongous hologram.
Yeah, humongous hologram.
Nice try, you guys, except
holograms don't rip through trees.
- Like, not even little ones?
- Sorry.
By the way, Miss Crystal,
if that is your real name...
how is it that you knew exactly which
button to push to shut off the system?
Uh, because it says off?
- Oh.
- If you ask me, Whirlen...
all this electronic fakery is exactly
what's doomed your school.
The students don't need to learn
a lot of hokey Las Vegas illusions.
They should learn the real
magic of O'Flannery Castle...
with all of its wonder and romance.
And do you have any stories
of romance you'd like to share?
Heh, heh. Heavens.
I'm just a caretaker.
I leave the storytelling
to the teachers.
And if the teachers are smart...
they'll treat the tradition of
O'Flannery Castle with more respect.
That's the reason the
griffin's come back.
What do you mean?
It's here to return the castle
to the days of true magic.
The way it should be.
Okay, okay, Miss Rumblebuns.
We get it. Thank you.
Well, no one can say she's not
passionate about her work.
Shaggy, Shaggy, Shaggy.
Oh, my gosh, I found it.
I found the magic staff.
You found the magic what? Yipe!
I was reading about Lord O'Flannery.
He used a special magic staff to
summon the griffin and control it.
Where is this magic staff?
Lord O'Flannery had it
placed in his tomb...
which is on an island right
here in Shadow Lake.
It's real close.
That's the same direction
the griffin came from.
You won't wanna be
going there, my friends.
What that fancy book won't tell you is
when Lord O'Flannery came from Ireland...
with him came his clan's banshee.
Banshee, like,
that's a good thing, right?
It's a hideous female ghost whose
wailing dooms whoever hears it.
Not listening.
Legend says the banshee
wailed over Lord O'Flannery...
as he breathed his last breath.
To this day, the ghost
guards his tomb...
ready to attack any who would
disturb the dark wizard's slumber.
You all have a pleasant evening.
Alrighty, who's up for pie?
Come on, Shaggy, we gotta find
that staff. It could be a clue.
Shadow Lake is a
quarter-mile ahead. Spooky.
We better stick together, gang.
Remember, that banshee
could be anywhere.
Man, no matter how hard I try,
I can't forget something like that.
All ashore who's going ashore.
We should be getting close, gang.
Through here.
How about we go over?
How did you do...? Oh!
Fred, you okay?
Yeah.
I guess we all have our
danger-prone days.
I think Scooby found something.
Check out this strange marking.
Each monolith has its own.
And I found another on the floor.
There's one here too.
Uh-oh.
Oh, well, I guess we'll never
get in that kooky crypt.
Let's head back to the
castle and make enchiladas.
It moved. Oh, man.
Shaggy did it.
Come on, I bet if we push it...
All right, everyone push.
A secret door. Let's go.
Scooby, run.
Hurry, Scoob.
Phew.
It's the O'Flannery crest.
Help me get the lid off.
That must be O'Flannery's staff.
And that must be O'Flannery.
- I'll get it.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Only the bravest hero
should retrieve it.
Oh, all right.
- Scooby, do you mind?
- Sorry, Shaggy.
It's okay. Thanks for the hand.
- Uh, uh, Shaggy.
- Zoinks.
Yup, that's me, Shaggy Rogers,
the bravest of heroes.
Shaggy, we have a visitor.
Then, like, why is
nobody saying hello?
Uh-huh. Bravest of heroes.
So that's the banshee?
She doesn't look scary.
Yeah, she looks kind of pretty.
Out here.
We gotta get back to the boat.
We can't leave the staff. Come on.
- Where'd they go?
- They'll be here.
Let's get the boat turned around.
Madelyn!
Coming through.
Push us off, Shaggy.
Nice footwork, Shaggy.
Let's get this back to the
castle and analyze it for clues.
I can't believe how you
saved us like that.
Yeah, well, I do have
some major feet.
It's more than your feet,
Shaggy. It's you.
You're so amazing, so forceful.
I think you're the bravest,
most wonderful boy I have ever known.
Oh, gee, Madelyn. I...
I like you too.
Aw. Mwah, mwah, mwah.
It's getting late.
What are you waiting for?
Directions? Drive!
Shoo, griffin.
Like, be gone already.
I think the batteries are dead.
Hey, I put a box of magic explosives
in the van for practice on the field.
Like, Scooby-Doo,
let's strike this griffin out.
Yeah, strike-out.
Uh-oh. I think Scooby dropped
a live explosive in the box.
- Like, which one?
- I can't tell.
We haven't lost him yet, guys.
Hurry, inside.
Hey, you're gonna leave me out here?
What's all the ruckus?
Griffin attack, run.
Huh?
Let's get the staff to Whirlen.
Oh, no.
Like, don't do it.
- Madelyn!
- Velma!
Oh, no.
Mr. Curdles, events have taken
a terrible turn over here.
You might wanna see for yourself.
I don't understand.
Why are you taking
all these magic tricks?
They're the only weapons
we have against the griffin.
But you don't even know
where the griffin's taken her.
We have a pretty good idea.
We believe it's called the
Griffin's Roost for a reason.
The Griffin's Roost?
But it's not safe.
The whole place is liable to
crash down on your heads.
We'll be careful. Besides, if there are
any clues I'm sure we'll find them there.
Like, I'm ready.
Why are you wearing armor?
Because even with this magic doohickey,
I need all the protection I can get.
Whirly, are you all right?
This griffin business
has beaten me, Marlon.
It's time to bring down the
curtain on this magic school.
My dream.
Touching. Touching.
Your most heartfelt
performance, Whirlen.
Now, rejoice.
Kindly Calvin Curdles is here with the
silver lining to your cloud of despair.
- How did you get in?
- Through the door.
I'm prepared to take thismonster-
blighted castle off your hands.
I'll even give you
a third... No, no, no.
Make that an 8th of
what you paid for it.
Well, this is hardly the time
for real-estate transactions.
When it comes to business matters...
Calvin Curdles was never one
to consider people's feelings.
Now, now, Alma,
perhaps I'm doing us all a favor.
You've said there was no griffin
before these 2 took over the castle.
- But we're not to blame.
- It's okay, Marlon.
Where do I sign?
I think you should
wait till we get back.
There's more to this griffin
business than meets the eye.
You know, I really,
really don't like her.
Just give us an hour. Let's go, guys.
- What happened?
- Like, it was the banshee.
But she split when Scooby tripped.
It's a wire.
- What is it, a camera?
- I don't think so, Fred.
Help! Help!
Madelyn.
Madelyn? Where?
Up here.
Help! Help!
Help!
Can anybody hear me? Help!
The stair moved.
Here's a way out.
Help! Help!
She's on the other side.
Try the staff again.
The staff?
Like, you shall not pass, man.
It worked.
It didn't work.
We're done for.
Not yet.
Let him have it.
The smoke bombs.
Run!
Shaggy, Scooby, are you okay?
Like, I think I still
have all my pieces.
Stay there, we'll come
back with help.
That's the best idea
I've heard, like, ever.
- The griffin.
- It's back.
But, like, Fred told
us to stay right here.
Help! Help! Can anybody hear me?
Like, she'll probably be okay
until help comes, don't you think?
Shaggy, Madelyn likes you.
Well, since you put
it that way, Scoob.
Like, dude, peep that crazy lock,
and that's without the key.
Shaggy, look.
Huh?
Good work, Scoob.
Yeah.
Shaggy.
- Hey, Mads, you okay?
- I am now.
I mean, the griffin dropped me
in the tower, then flew off.
I hope he doesn't come
back for a midnight snack.
Quick, Scooby-Doo, pull something out
of that bag that will help us escape.
Okay.
We can climb down on these.
Like, I don't know.
It seems kind of flimsy.
- Come on.
- Go.
Like, beat it, Tweety.
Where's the seat belt on this thing?
Those kids won't find anything.
Why delay the inevitable?
I suppose you're right.
But I do hate letting
down my students.
Oh, yes, it's a tragedy.
Sign here, please.
The griffin is in the old tower.
Come on.
There they are.
Shaggy, try the staff again.
- Dude, it's a fake.
- Just try.
I totally command you.
By the powers of Houdini,
the Wizard of Oz...
and, um, the English
kid with the glasses...
to put us down.
Like, dude, we're losing altitude.
Little help, little help!
Shaggy got him.
Isn't that incredible?
Yeah.
You really are brave.
Like, don't squeeze me, Madelyn.
You're denting my metal.
The poor thing looks hurt.
Why doesn't it fly away?
There's your answer.
- The griffin, it's a gigantic puppet?
- Correct.
This whole charade
is making sense now.
Run!
Whoa.
Marlon, you?
Marlon operated that contraption trying
to scare everyone away once and for all.
But Shaggy and Scooby
spoiled his plans.
So the monster never was real.
No, just a more sophisticated version
of the puppets in your magic act...
when you and Marlon were kids.
The blimp carried the griffin beneath
it to make it look like it was flying.
But how did he disguise the blimp?
Remember how every time the
griffin appeared, it was foggy?
The blimp generated its
own concealing fog bank.
I noticed some of the bottles in
Marlon's workshop were marked glycerol.
A chemical used by professional
illusionists in fog machines.
I used the fog to hide the blimp...
then worked the griffin through
this handheld animatronic control.
What about when the griffin
attacked us in the tower?
- It couldn't have been the same puppet.
- It wasn't.
After Whirlen bought the castle,
I started renovating the Griffin's Roost.
I discovered Lord O' Flannery had rigged
parts of the tower with devices of his own...
to make superstitious people
think a monster lived there.
When trespassers entered the tower...
they would be driven away
by the attacking griffin.
I kept the secret to myself...
and outfitted the worn-out machinery
with state-of-the-art equipment.
Okay, but who is the banshee?
- Another puppet, right?
- Partially.
Marlon had several rigged to
appear in various places.
Even in the lake, to make it
look like she was chasing us.
She wasn't a puppet every time.
Yes, I realized that when we
saw the device in the tower.
It was really a projector Marlon
uses for his volumetric displays.
One of many.
Anyone entering the tower would
have set off an invisible electric eye...
activating the ghost.
Marlon's technology was a lot more
sophisticated than he was letting on.
Marlon, why did you do this?
Because all my life I've been
jealous, jealous of you.
While I did all the work,
you got all the applause.
I finally decided I wanted
to create my own magic act.
With my puppets and projections,
I could become a magic sensation.
Why didn't you?
Because I needed money
to start the act.
The only way I could get it is if
you agreed to sell the castle...
which I knew you wouldn't do
unless you were forced to.
I didn't mean to hurt anyone, honest.
All I wanted to do
was scare people away.
I tried to make amends. After the
automated griffin wrecked the bridge,
I flew back in the blimp
to bring you down.
But these 2 fearless souls attacked
me before I could explain.
- Hey, how did the griffin crash anyway?
- Here's your answer.
The magic staff?
Like, I guess, it really did
control the monster after all.
Aw, I'm so ashamed.
Who would have thought that
miserable Marlon would be behind this?
You would. You knew all along.
Of course, Amos was the only one who
was never afraid to be out at night.
He must have known
the griffin was a fake.
Amos probably followed Marlon to the
Griffin's Roost while he was rebuilding it.
I saw him going in there, day and night,
with loads of strange-looking crates.
So I got nosy and peeked.
Yes, and my guess is he
told you, Mr. Curdles.
You weren't worried
about the griffin.
You could even use it to get
a cheap price on the castle.
- Wow. These girlies are smart.
- Oh, shut up.
No need to deny it, Mr. Curdles.
Your story about turning the
castle into a restaurant...
never made sense in the first place.
You were really buying it for
Miss Rumblebuns, weren't you?
Calvin, is this true?
Yes, Alma, it is. I meant
for it to be a surprise.
You see, years ago, I operated a
struggling ice-cream concession here...
for the few tourists who
visited O' Flannery Castle.
It was here that I met the
castle's dazzling caretaker,
Miss Alma Rumblebuns.
Ah. We were so much in love.
Fearing that a high-born
creature of Alma's caste...
could never settle for a
mere sherbet jockey, I left.
Determined someday to return
a frozen-novelty mogul.
Alas, I became so swept up in the
intoxicating world of cream and cones...
I never came back.
But I couldn't forget you, Alma.
I thought that if I bought you this
castle which you loved so much...
you might love me again.
Oh, Calvin, I don't know what to say.
Well, just say you forgive me.
Ew.
Please, Whirlen,
I will double the price.
Don't do it, Whirlen,
I couldn't take the money now.
Not when I've seen what
the school means to you.
I was wrong.
My place is here with you...
passing on what we've discovered
to kids who truly wanna learn.
They're the ones I've really hurt.
I think there's time to make amends.
Starting with the education of our
new apprentice, Madelyn Dinkley.
Really? You mean it?
With your enthusiasm
and our coaching,
you could be the next
big thing in magic.
Congratulations, Madelyn.
You deserve it.
I must admit, you handled yourself
pretty well on this adventure.
Thanks.
I guess we Dinkley sisters have
something in common after all.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
The Cone Castle Creamery, makers
of those cones that make you moan...
is proud to sponsor
the very first show...
by the students of the Merlin
Brothers' Academy of Magic.
And now your hosts,
Marlon and Whirlen...
the Brothers Merlin.
- Isn't she adorable?
- Yeah.
- Hey, shouldn't you be up there with her?
- I've been training an assistant.
- How did you do that?
- That's my secret, scarf boy.
- Like, that was totally awesome, Mads.
- Thanks, Shaggy.
Hey, have you seen Scooby-Doo?
- Oh.
- Let's go, move, move.
Looks like your dog is
braver than you thought.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you. And thank you.
Scooby-abracadabra-Doo!